The passion, the violence, the birth of America's Gilded Age.
Ragtime is a drama, history film directed by Miloš Forman.
A young black pianist becomes embroiled in the lives of an upper-class white family set among the racial
tensions, infidelity, violence, and other nostalgic events in early 1900s New York City.
New York Police Commissioner Rhinelander Waldo, played by James Cagney.
Younger Brother, played by Brad Dourif.
Booker T. Washington, played by Moses Gunn.
Evelyn Nesbit, played by Elizabeth McGovern.
Willie Conklin, played by Kenneth McMillan.
Delmas, played by Pat O'Brien.
Ragtime is a 1981 American drama film directed by Miloš Forman,
based on the 1975 historical novel Ragtime by E.
It is set in and around New York City at the start of the 20th century, New Rochelle, and Atlantic
City, and includes fictionalized references to actual people and events of the time.
The film stars James Cagney, Mary Steenburgen, Howard Rollins,
Brad Dourif, James Olson and Elizabeth McGovern.
Ragtime featured Cagney's and Pat O'Brien's final film appearances, as well as early
roles for Jeff Daniels (his film debut), Fran Drescher, Samuel L.
Jackson, Ethan Phillips, and John Ratzenberger.
The film explores themes of new york city, based on novel or book,
jazz singer or musician, public murder, racism.
The tone is emotional.